Keith Chen



yonghengzero@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/keith-chen-88205b199



+8617722682344



http://github.com/WindSoilder

Summary

Profile

I am a experience software engineer, mainly working as a backend engineer, programming in python and rust. With strong experience in back-end development, design RESTFUL api independently. As well as collaborate with team member.

Personally, I'm care about unit testing, documentation, writing readable and testable code.

Fan of solving problems, writing code, and contributing to open source projects.

Skills

programming languages: python, rust.

Back-End Framework and Databases: flask/fastapi, celery, mongodb, mysql, redis, rabbitmq(mainly used with celery)

Testing and Automation Frameworks: pytest, unittest.mock

Solid basic computer knowledge includes Computer network(HTTP/TCP/IP), Data structure, basic algorithm.

Experience with kunernetes and docker basic usage.

Experience



Software Engineer

深圳米筐科技有限公司

Apr 2018 - Present (3 years 7 months +)

Redesign and write internal http service named performance attribution(https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ Performance_attribution) for customer, accomplished:

- 1. required much less memory(from 32G to 8G)
- 2. gained much more performance(reduce 70% of the runtime in the general scenario)
- 3. get more extendable and easily testing service.

Write financial data ETL program, the etl program transfer daily financial market data from `mysql/ oracle` to `mongodb`, supports both high-performance incremental dump and full dump.

Prompt the usage of rust in company, rewrite some internal components in rust. Generally, It's 3.5x faster than the original one.

Prompt and rewrite a new C-S based mongodb synchronizer, it supports sync internal mongodb data to customer. User can specific which database, which collection to sync.

After a careful design, the syncer accomplished:

- 1. during client full synchronized progress, the origin database can provide services as usual(no directly increasing workload)
- 2. customer get reliable and realtime update from original database.
- 3. less mongodb instance is used in the company(from 4 to 1).

I'm also working on something includes:

- a. Finance service developments
- b. design RESTFUL api
- c. makes some profile and performance improvement for existing code base.

Tools & Technologies: Python3(pandas + pytest + FASTAPI + celery + mypy), Rust, RESTFUL api design, distributed computing, rust, mongodb, Jira, Jenkins, Confluence

Ouest Associate Software Developer

Dell Cloud Manager (now part of Quest Software)

Jun 2016 - Apr 2018 (1 year 11 months)

Firstly I'm using python + robotframework to build UAT automation testing for product, and involve in improving testing code performance, which reduces running time from 2hours to 1hour.

Then involve in product development, which mainly using C# and powershell.

Tools & Technologies:

Python, Robotframework, test automation, agile methodologies, C#, AWS, Confluence, Jira, Jenkins



Test Development Engineer

Alibaba Group

Jun 2015 - Aug 2015 (3 months)

Test Development Engineer, Jun 2015 - Aug 2015

Mainly working on testing security product.

The test process includes: Functional Testing, Performance Testing, Stability Testing

Tools & Technologies:

Python, automation tests

Education



Guangdong University of Technology

Bachelor's degree, Computer Software Engineering 2012 - 2016

Skills

Back-End Web Development • Rust (Programming Language) • Python (Programming Language) • Git • Extract, Transform, Load (ETL) • Flask • Celery